Brandon Corey

in brandonmcorey | □ brandoncorey.dev | ♠ brandoncorey | ■ bcorey3660@gmail.com | ♦ Foxborough, MA

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer with experience in full-stack development and data analysis. I am familiar with various programming languages and cloud technologies. I became interested in programming through my analytics work, resulting in a shift in focus towards development.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Co-Creator

01/2024-present

DataLoaf, Remote US

- DataLoaf (data-loaf.com ☑) is a self-hosted, open-source product analytics solution for small teams
- Developed a TypeScript querying service to facilitate event data retrieval and processing via a REST api
- Orchestrated AWS infrastructure setup and automation via a CLI tool written in Go that utilized Terraform to provision or tear down 50+ resources with a single command
- Implemented a scalable real-time event delivery pipeline using Amazon S3, Amazon Data Firehose, and Amazon Redshift, transferring up to 1 million events per second
- Developed a React frontend that utilized DaisyUI and TailwindCSS to display aggregations based on event type, aggregation, time-frame, and user/event filters
- Leveraged Docker with EC2 for deployment of backend services and Nginx for serving the front-end application
- Developed an SDK that sends requests to Amazon API gateway to place data into pipeline
- Authored 10+ SQL queries to perform common analytics aggregations to execute against Amazon Redshift
- Implemented a Python User Defined Function (UDF) for complex filtering of event and user attributes

Marketing Analyst (B2B) 06/2022 - 04/2023

Wayfair, Boston MA

- Utilized Google BigQuery to author advanced SQL scripts that aggregated email engagement data for reporting
- · Wrote and maintained supplier contact script used for customer segmentation in all Supplier Marketing campaigns
- · Used JavaScript UDFs and stored procedures in BigQuery to abstract functions that were routinely executed
- Leveraged Data Studio to create/maintain dashboard visualizations for supplier segmentation data
- Used DataDog and Grafana to set up slack alerts for email campaigns that were not operating as intended
- Automated internal emails based on event triggers via JavaScript's Google suite integration

</> </> SKILLS

Backend Node, TypeScript, Go/Golang, Python, SQL, MongoDB, Express

Frontend JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Query, TailwindCSS, DaisyUI, HTML, CSS, Recharts

Cloud/Infra

Terraform, Docker, Nginx, AWS (EC2, Kinesis, Redshift, Lambda, S3, API Gateway, Cloudwatch)

Other

Git, Github, Linux, HTTP, Websockets, SSE, REST, Jest, React Testing Library, BubbleTea, Cobra

EDUCATION

2019 - 2022

B.S in Managerial Economics, College of Social & Behavioral Sciences

Launch School ☑ 2022 - 2024

Online program focused on Software Engineering fundamentals